Hey, Cho.
Okay, how'd you do that?
Well, you tread
a little heavier than Lisbon
and Rigby's car isn't in the lot.
We've got a case and Lisbon's busy.
So you and I are riding out.
- Excellent. I'll meet you downstairs.
- Okay.
Quaint.
Yeah.
I'm Kimball Cho.
This is Patrick Jane.
County Coroner, Deb Granger.
Pleased to meet you.
We don't get to work a lot
of murders around here.
You got a little, uh,
something on your...
Oh. Brain matter. Good catch.
Victim's name is Hollis Percy.
61 years of age.
His wife found him this morning.
- And he owned the town of Percy.
- The whole town?
Yeah. Schools, roads, bakery...
been in his family
since the gold rush.
Not exactly booming
by the looks of it.
They still get a little tourism
off the highway.
Smells of juniper.
Cologne?
Uh, I don't... no.
More like...
Cheap gin...
drunken out of necessity, not pleasure.
So, he drank alone.
He let the killer in.
He knew him or her.
- They argued...
- How'd you know they argued?
- Well, he is dead.
- What did they argue about?
Well, I don't know.
What do people argue about?
- Money, power, love, jealousy...
- Revenge...
- Sorry, I shouldn't do that.
- Oh, no. Jump right in.
This is a murder. It's exciting.
What's your guess
on time of death?
Rigor stiffness suggests
12 hours or more.
Probably that's your murder weapon.
It's an antique.
Colt 1851 Navy. .36 caliber.
Probably hasn't been fired
in a century.
Right. So, instead, your guy...
or gal...
- Whack.
Penetrating trauma
to the back of the skull
was introduced
by the butt of the gun.
Once I pop the calvarium, I'll know
if that's our official cause of death.
That's great.
Let's pop the calvarium.
- You two hold here.
- What is...
- We're gonna hold here.
- Oh, okay.
- They've got this covered.
- Yeah.
"Listen up!"
Like I said, folks, anything
can happen here
in rough 'n' tumble
Percy, California.
Let's... Wait... let's have uh... uh,
a big round of applause
for our modern-day
gunslingers here, yeah.
What the hell are you doing?
This is a crime scene.
Don't you know
there's a dead body in there?
These people paid 25 bucks
each in advance.
- They're entitled to a show.
- Well, they got one.
Now shut this down
and clear the area right now.
"I don't know."
I think that's why I liked
San Francisco.
I never saw myself living
in the place I grew up.
You know?
Yeah. I know.
What about you?
Where did you grow up?
Oh, we moved around...
for Dad's work,
and then for Mom's work...
I like to say I grew up in America.
Yeah. Yeah.
Um...
I hate to do this,
but I have to run.
We have a fresh case.
Please. I'm glad we were able
to do this...
sit down like this.
This is nice.
You're really easy
to talk to, Teresa.
Thanks, Bob.
Are there any new lines
of inquiry on Red John?
We've had some leads, but...
I hate to admit it...
we're kinda stuck.
Nothing. No.
- What about Jane?
- I don't think he has anything.
But he'd tell you if he did.
Yeah. Yeah, he would.
Okay. Well, I'm sure we'll talk.
Homeland Security beckons.
- Is it cold in here?
- Yeah. AC's on the fritz,
It's stuck on cold.
They got someone coming in.
- So I'm not crazy, okay.
- Right.
Percy, California.
Incorporated by J.D. Percy
as a trading post in 1870.
Trade dried up,
but the Percy family stayed.
They tried to make it work.
It's basically been a tourist town
for the past 30 years.
But that hasn't been
going too great.
Sorry. It was
a "welcome back" gift.
Very thoughtful, Wayne.
- Well, how did you know it was from me?
- I'm a homicide detective.
Now, Hollis Percy owned
every building.
People pay him rent,
and he was the bank.
That property belongs to his wife,
Joanna, for a few weeks, anyway.
- Well, why only a few weeks?
- He ran outta money.
The Wild West Show
was a last-ditch chance
to drum up some cash, but now
the whole place is up for sale.
- They started selling property this year.
- Houses, stores.
People rented for generations
and now becoming owners.
- A lotta money changing hands.
- There could be motive there.
Go through all
the real estate transactions...
see if anything shakes loose.
- Any usable prints on the gun?
- Doesn't look that way.
Okay. I'm gonna go talk
to the family.
Make sure they take care
of this AC today.
- That was it?
- That's all Kirkland said.
He was just fishing.
Don't you think it's odd...
Homeland Security's fascination
with a California serial killer?
Everything about
Bob Kirkland is odd.
- Well, yes.
- Just add that to the list.
Hello there.
Emmett Cook, chief of police.
Sorry I couldn't be
at the crime scene.
Yeah, why couldn't you be there?
Something a little more pressing
than a murder?
I'm Agent Lisbon,
and this is Patrick Jane.
- Hi.
Um, actually, I couldn't be there
'cause I was dealing with a fire.
Quite a mess, uh,
third one this year.
These, uh, meth labs guys
are setting up in empty cabins, uh...
the things go...
Kablooey.
Kablooey, indeed.
So you've been busy, Chief?
Do you think the drug trade
had something to do
with Hollis Percy's murder?
I don't see the connection. No.
I mean, there could be,
but that would be...
Uh, messy?
- Yes... You could say that.
- I did.
Well, I just wanted
to stop by and let you know
that I am available
if CBI needs my help.
Thank you, but that's kind
of a conflict of interest.
You aiding in the investigation
of the murder
of the man
who pays your salary.
Well, plus you've got some
meth dealers to track down.
Yes. Yes, I do.
Well, if you need anything,
just, um...
shout.
We'll holler.
Very odd little
country welcome.
- You've had no issues, Mrs. Percy?
- No.
There's been no trouble.
The last murder
in Percy was a long time ago.
It's safe here.
We have good schools.
We... we build riding trails and...
and Hollis maintained it
all beautifully.
Dad loved this town.
- But you don't... Ian?
- Of course he does.
Yeah. I mean, you know?
- Well, it's not a trick question.
- No, of course.
I just moved back
to help with the transition.
I was in San Francisco
working venture capital.
It was time to come home.
Was Hollis meeting someone
in his office last night?
We think the attack took place
around 8:00.
Well, it's possible.
He kept a lotta late hours
the past few years.
Yeah, he tried everything...
talking to investors, developers
but, you know,
towns like this are just dying out.
Still, he was a feudal lord ruling over
a town of downtrodden serfs.
He must have had someone
that hated him.
He was respected.
Ask anyone.
What about the sale
of the town?
Was there any friction there?
So he had a few critics.
Could you do me a favor?
Just grab a piece of paper
there and a pen
and write down the name
that you just thought of, just now.
Write it down.
Don't show it to each other.
- Why?
- Please?
Francisco Navarro.
And you had the same thought.
- Who is Francisco Navarro?
- He runs a Wild West Show.
He's an old friend
of the family...
and he didn't think
we should sell.
Hollis did what he had to do.
A bunch of amateurs
playing cowboys and Indians
weren't gonna save us no matter
what Francisco believed.
He's pretty dedicated to this place.
You think he was angry enough
to act on it?
Like I said... He's dedicated.
That's a nice jacket, Mr. Navarro.
What would you call that...
a duster?
I'm the medicine man in the show.
I'm going right there from here.
Just answer the question.
Yes. It's a duster.
- Are you writing that down?
- Tell me about the Wild West Show.
Our program is a fully immersive
step back in the 19th century.
I oversee 20 performers.
We run six days a week.
Wednesdays and Fridays
we stage a medicine man show.
"And you're in charge?"
"Which makes this piece
on your blog..."
kind of odd.
- "Killing Percy."
- Well, I meant the town of Percy
- not Hollis Percy, obviously.
- Yeah. That's some bad timing.
Yes, it is.
It is also the inalienable right
of every citizen
in the state of California
to freely speak, write,
and publish his sentiments
on all subjects. I overreacted...
online.
I would never do harm
to my friend.
- But he wasn't your friend.
- No, he was.
But... when he started
selling property last year
See, that's just giving up on something
worth fighting for. He was weak.
And he couldn't afford
to run the town?
Which meant your show
was gonna get shut down.
Yeah, and what thanks do I get?
I built our program
to save Percy.
Tourists came...
just not enough.
And then with these cabins
exploding up there in the woods
"it's getting ugly."
Where were you last night
at 8:00 p.m.?
I was in the bar
with some of my actors.
If you're so dialed into the town
who else had a beef
with your friend?
I have no idea. Look, I gotta go.
I have a show to put on.
"His alibi relies on the account
of a bunch of drunks."
Real drunks
or old-timey pioneer drunks
that are getting paid
by the hour?
Well, either way, he could have left
the bar at any point
walked 30 yards
to Hollis' office, and walked out.
Oh, we're heading
to the bar now.
All right. We're gonna go meet
the police chief.
And then Rigsby wants to go
check out those cabins.
The meth lab fires? Might be worth
looking into, I guess.
Follow close as my magical and mysterious
friend Mr. Golden Nugget
travels a trail of deception
before your very eyes.
Young man, under which
of these humble chalices
does the golden nugget reside?
That one.
A brave choice
but sadly, the wrong one.
Hey! Care to wager again?
A buck buys three guesses
but pays 5
if you guess right.
I-I believe
I-I saw your move.
Oh, what have we here...
A skeptic?
Please sir, step right up.
Test my skills.
See if you remain unconvinced.
- Don't mind if I do. Okay...
- All right.
So the nugget goes
in the cup like this.
And then we move them
around like this
until I can't tell
which one it's in.
Then you continue doing that,
but then to do this
don't you need to have
a gold nugget?
I believe I saw
your move there, friend.
- You did, did you?
- You won't mind?
- Not at all. Not one little bit.
- Uh, now, come on.
- What?
- You know I felt that.
- Felt what?
- My wallet, please.
I beg your pardon?
- Sir.
- I-I mean, this?
Oh, this. Is this it?
I've never seen that in my life.
- So you're schooled in the craft?
- Yeah, I used to be.
I'm a little rusty.
But you know what? Worth a shot.
- Wait a minute! Where's my gold?
- What?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Bro, that thing is real.
All right, sir. We will get you
your gold back.
- Jane.
- I don't have your gold.
Maybe the kid
can enlighten you.
The ki...
Here we go, Lisbon...
Gossip.
Two sarsaparillas, please.
Sure I can't Irish those up for ya?
Oh, would that I could,
but we're on the job.
Are you guys here
about the murder?
I mean, not that you stand out
in your suits or anything, but...
We're with the CBI.
Yes. Um, can I ask you...
Do they let you use
your real name in this shop?
I guess. Um, I'm Lily...
Soto.
You looked a little spooked
just then.
- Did you know Hollis?
- Barely.
I grew up in Jasper...
in the valley.
He interviewed me for this job
like a year ago.
Did his employees like him?
Yeah. Yeah, I mean,
he tips us out at Christmas.
He's generous...
too much, probably.
Well, I imagine that some people
bad-mouth him
once the booze starts to flow.
Oh. I mean, you know,
people talk.
Some people weren't happy
with the way he was
running the town.
He kept this place going.
Yeah, but it's... it's been getting
bad for a while.
Rumor is there's a mall moving in.
Like, wow, right? But...
People are freaking out
about these meth labs.
Some friends were gonna
buy the bar
but everybody's moving away.
Francisco Navarro... was he here
last night at 8:00 p.m.?
Yeah. Yeah. I mean, he's pretty much
here every night.
You would be, too,
if you drank for free.
Is that on?
Probably not since disco.
Hollis Percy overpaid
his workers.
He hired three bartenders
when two would suffice.
And yet he's dead.
So, do you think
his generosity got him killed?
I just think it's odd
that such a swell guy
felt compelled to pay
for loyalty.
So the police have no surveillance
footage on Main Street.
Nope.
And we follow up by driving
out to the woods. Why?
Timing.
An explosion the night
before a murder...
doesn't that seem suspicious
to you?
Not really. They're meth labs.
They explode.
Well, let me ask you this.
Doesn't something look
off here?
Yeah, everything's burned.
Yeah, but this is not
completely torched.
- Feel that.
- I'm good.
It feels like a flame-retardant gel.
That's why some of this stuff
here survived.
Before this place burned down
someone...
someone sprayed it down
so that the flames wouldn't
spread into a forest fire.
- So this wasn't an accident?
- No.
Okay.
- Then, what was it?
- So you think it was arson?
Well, maybe it was a rival gang trying
to make a point, like a territorial thing?
Yeah, but what kinda drug dealer
sprays the place down for safety?
I don't know.
There might be a connection
to Hollis' murder here.
It's weird.
It's almost as if someone
mocked these places up
to make them look like meth labs.
Okay, you and Cho look into it.
Uh, put your toolboxes down, please.
Here to fix the air conditioning.
All right.
We're at the door.
30 seconds till we're in.
Go ahead. Say it.
Then you're supposed
to say, "Say what?"
And then I say, "You think I'm an idiot
for buying Van Pelt that orchid."
You know what?
I'm glad I did.
'Cause now the ball's
in her court.
I'm gonna be so Zen
about this.
Yep, the next move's hers.
I'm just gonna be the reed
that bends in the breeze.
You're still in love with her.
But instead of telling her,
you bought her a plant.
Yeah, that's pretty Zen, though.
Right?
Hey, fellas.
We're gonna need this space.
How long are you boys
gonna be fiddling
with those new fangled
contraptions there?
CBI arson unit, sir.
We'll be done shortly.
Look, Mr. Navarro's kicking my butt...
trying to get the show
back up here.
We've been shut down
all day.
Hi. I'm Ian Percy.
I'm in charge here.
Are you gentlemen
with the CBI?
Yes, Mr. Percy. I'm Agent Cho.
This is Agent Rigsby.
- CBI arson unit.
- Arson unit?
We're driving up
to check out those cabin fires.
Hitting it bright and early
tomorrow morning.
Oh, it's arson, you think?
Isn't that...
wasn't it supposed to be
some crystal meth mishap?
Well, fortunately
it didn't all burn down.
Once we get the chemical
signature of the burn
we can tell if someone
torched it.
We'll find our bad guy
pretty quick after that.
Let me know if you need
anything from me.
In the meantime,
I'll let you get back to it.
Hello, Chief.
You got no case.
You're wasting your time.
So, you saw me carrying
a gas can. Big deal.
Besides, you didn't even take
your fancy equipment outta the truck.
Yeah, there was no fancy equipment.
Just your guilty conscience.
Want something to drink?
It's a long drive back
to Sacramento.
You look cozy there, Chief.
He knows how this goes.
He's a cop.
And you're a crook, too, right?
That's why you built these phony
meth labs, burned 'em down?
And you were trying
to scare people away.
Drive down prices
and buy property on the cheap.
Look...
even if I did set
a couple cabins on fire...
So what?
Maybe I like fires.
Listen, Emmett...
this isn't hypothetical.
Right now, you're our prime suspect
in this murder case.
You know what to do.
You don't wanna be wrapped up
in a murder investigation.
Help yourself out.
All right, look, um, the thing
is in about three to four years
a new outlet mall
is gonna open here...
uh, next to Percy.
So I figure I could
hold onto the land till then.
- Then... dump it?
- But Hollis figured it out?
- And he confronted you?
- No.
- Hollis was clueless.
- So what did happen?
My colleague here
thinks you killed him.
So far I can't tell
if you have the stones.
No... no...
No, guys...
Guys, I'm...
Hollis didn't suspect a thing,
I'm telling you.
He was just some rich... weirdo.
- They both are.
- They? Who's they? The son?
Joanna... his wife.
Uh, two weeks ago,
I get a call to the house...
the neighbor heard
some screaming.
He was drunk.
And she was outta control...
shrieking.
Shrieking... about what?
Jane made a lotta
Red John connections here.
It looks like he's building
his own time line.
It's all on the drive. We printed out
some greatest hits.
- This is good.
- We could log it into the system.
- Not necessary.
- So you'll just... take it from here?
I will.
He was sober for 20 years.
A month ago, he fell off the wagon
and he could be a mean drunk.
Did he hit you?
- No.
- No?
Okay.
What could have caused him
to start drinking again?
Well, he had his triggers.
But his father's been dead a long time.
Were there romantic problems?
You're sweet.
You mean, was Hollis sleeping around?
Or maybe you found out.
Maybe you argued, and he was drunk
and things got outta control.
Hollis used to run around.
He was fun...
too much fun.
But he grew to be faithful.
He was terrified of change.
A wife knows.
If you were married, you'd understand
what I was talking about.
Are you married, Agent Van Pelt?
Not yet. Sounds like fun.
I like the police chief for the murder.
He's a weasel.
Real estate records show
that Cook
and some poorly rigged holding
company bought properties in town.
He had a lot to lose
if Hollis exposed his scam.
Juicy stuff.
You have him pegged right as a weasel
but I don't think he's a killer.
I think Joanna hides it well,
but Hollis may have been abusive.
You're thinking self-defense.
There is one vexing detail still missing.
Something in Hollis' life changed...
a month ago.
You mean, to get him drinking again.
Yeah, exactly. Something.
We have to figure out what it was.
Okay. How?
Well, Joanna has no idea
or she has no inclination to tell us.
Nor does anyone else.
Maybe something
in his past re-emerged.
- That's thin.
- Yeah. That is thin.
But you have to start somewhere.
Beautiful orchid, Grace.
Well-chosen, Rigsby.
Hey.
Set you up with another sarsaparilla?
- On the house.
- Ah. Who'd say no to that?
I'm gonna get going. Agent Jane.
- See you around.
- Sure thing, Mr. Percy.
Mr. Percy? Very formal.
Uh, well, you know, it pays to kiss
the ring.
So, you cracked your case yet?
Cracked, uh, mm...
not likely. No.
Uh, when does Francisco
usually show up here?
He should be here soon.
I heard you clowned Kevin pretty good.
Kevin... the magician.
Oh, him. Yes. Wouldn't call him
a magician.
Normally has to be magic involved.
Yeah.
I hear you got real powers.
No, I... just a little mind reading
and predictions, that's all.
Show me.
Please?
Okay.
How about I tell you what you're gonna
have for breakfast tomorrow morning?
Okay.
I'm gonna need a pen, paper,
and an envelope.
Tasty.
- Voila.
- Thank you.
Close your eyes.
I want you to imagine being
in your kitchen tomorrow morning.
This is what I like about tending bar...
you meet all kinds.
Visualize yourself...
looking into the cupboard...
looking at all the items thinking
about what you're gonna eat.
And then you choose
which one you want.
- You got it? You sure?
- Yeah.
Okay.
Done.
Put it somewhere safe.
We'll open it tomorrow.
- No peeking.
- Oh, I wouldn't dream of it.
Barmaid!
Shot of whiskey and a beer back.
- What do you need?
- Backup.
I don't like it when you say
you need backup
and nothing's happened yet.
Nothing to worry about.
We're just here to talk.
Uh, do you mind?
Oh, she didn't have to go anywhere.
I already said my piece, but go ahead.
Well, we're interested
in ancient history...
which seems to be your department
so it's obvious that we start
with you.
We wanna know
about Hollis Percy's drinking.
Well, he used to drink
and then he stopped.
Then he started again.
You have any idea why?
Well, who knows
what drives any other man?
- Mr. Navarro, answer the question.
- Let's try this another way.
Y-you and Hollis used
to knock around together...
- you're lifelong buddies, huh?
- Yeah, we used to have some fun.
Well, it seems there was nothing
in his current life
that would drive him to drink,
so I am guessing
it was something from his old life
that came outta the woodwork.
Or someone. Tell me...
how far off am I?
No idea what you're talking about.
Really?
You know what I find sad?
The way you're so tucked
in the Percy family pocket.
- Tucked in their pocket?
- Yeah. Like a soiled hankie.
- You got a problem here, boss?
- No. No problem.
No we're... we're fine.
Okay? We're good?
You are hiding information
from the police, though
which is a crime.
- Why would I do that?
- Well, possibly to protect yourself
by protecting Hollis Percy.
I'm not sure.
- What's he talking about?
- He doesn't know.
Yes, but you do.
You talk a big game about fighting
for this town, fighting for the staff.
But the truth is you sold out
to Hollis a long time ago.
So long ago, you probably thought
he was your friend
which is not sad... that's just stupid.
You son of a bitch!
Maybe we got a problem.
- Is this part of the show?
- "Knock it off!"
No.
He coulda asked nicely,
that's all I was saying.
I was there.
- You want more coffee?
- No, I'm good.
And Jane thinks you know
who came after Hollis Percy.
Based on what, precisely?
Well, we don't need to be precise.
You do.
Okay.
Yeah, we got into some trouble
when we were kids.
Hollis got involved
with this one crazy girl...
townie from a few miles up the road...
she was pretty.
This was right after he married Joanna.
He do that a lot?
- Slumming it with the local girls?
- Yeah, he did.
But this girl got pregnant.
And Hollis paid her to...
to deal with it.
Her brother found out...
uh, her brother was bad news.
He roughed up Hollis
pretty thoroughly.
And the brother held a grudge
this whole time.
Yeah, he might have.
He was in prison for 12 years.
He got out a month ago.
I thought maybe he came looking
for a handout from Hollis.
The rich guy he had dirt on.
- Something like that.
- What happened to the girl?
Well, we heard she went back home.
This was 30 years ago.
Hollis was a mess.
His dad found out...
almost disowned him.
- Poor guy.
- Yes, we had a falling out, but...
Hollis was always my friend.
And Ian... he had no idea.
He's a good kid.
And you may have given
your friend's killer a 2-day head start.
I need to know the guy's name...
the brother.
Flores. Dominic Flores.
- You gonna touch all of 'em?
- Haven't touched that one.
- I'm looking for poppy.
- Lisbon took it.
If you want poppy,
grab the everything bagel.
Yeah, but it has all that other stuff on it.
Like those onion scraps, I mean,
what are the point of those?
- All you see are problems.
- All I see are bagels.
Just make a choice.
Great.
Where are we with the brother...
Hollis' old buddy?
Oh, you mean Dominic Flores?
He's fresh outta Folsom
serving 12 years and 7 weeks
for robbing... what did it say?
16 jewelry stores and a pet shop.
Yeah. He stole a boa constrictor.
Of course he did.
He was released a month ago.
His parole officer says he's been diligent.
But the night of the murder
he was at a job fair in Sacramento.
The coroner puts the attack
at 8:00 p.m.
- He couldn't have been both places.
- I don't think so.
I spoke to a guy who had
a booth at the job fair...
a solar panel company.
He said Dominic signed in
for an interview at 7:45.
Okay. What about the sister, Juliana?
Still looking. She bounced around for a bit
then fell out of touch with the family.
So it's possible Dominic got out
and paid Hollis an awkward visit.
That might explain his drinking
but it doesn't explain his murder.
We should ask Joanna if she knew
about the pregnancy after the show.
- What do you mean?
- Jane says
we need to go
to the Medicine Man Show, obviously.
Rigsby, you wanna drive?
As long as I'm not called up
to volunteer, sure.
- Ah, Kevin.
- You again.
You know, I-I'm afraid
we got off on the wrong foot
and you need my help,
I need your help.
Maybe we can come to some
kind of agreement.
- Why do I need your help?
- Your magic sucks eggs.
I can help you with that,
and you can help me in return
by giving me a couple of minutes
of your stage time.
Sucks eggs, huh?
- Pick a card. I won't look.
- All right.
- Pick what card?
- You took my cards.
I don't know what you're talking about.
- Give me back my cards.
- Hey, hey, hey, Kevin...
Kevin, let's modulate the attitude.
- What's the problem?
- This guy is trying to get in my head.
He's trying to ruin my act.
He stole my cards.
Kevin, that's not true.
I-I think you should cool down
before you go anywhere
near an audience.
Stop playing with me.
Mr. Jane, maybe you'd be better
off taking your seat.
- I can handle this.
- Sure, I'd appreciate that.
- He's a little scary.
- Oh, you're gonna handle it, Francisco?
Handle this. I quit.
Here you go.
Candy-ass pickpocket tryin'
to bust my chops.
- I beg your pardon.
- Nobody handles me.
- What did you do?
- Who's he calling a candy-ass?
Well, now I have no magic show.
- Thank you. That's great...
- I know magic.
- Yeah?
- Yes. What's your favorite number?
- Uh, 23.
- Really?
Check that pocket, there.
- How'd you do that?
- Do I get the gig?
Hell, yeah!
- So what is it that Jane's gonna do?
- No idea.
Really?
Sometimes it's best just to be relaxed
about this stuff.
Welcome, ladies and gentlemen
and cowboys, too.
Now, you all are in for a frontier treat
that will mesmerize and amaze.
I'm proud to present to you
the daring work
of magician and mental mystic,
Patrick Jane!
Let's hear it for him!
Thank you, Doc Navarro.
Very impressive introduction.
I hope I don't disappoint.
Some people say I have special powers.
It's not true.
Everyone can read minds.
I can just do it marginally better
than most, that's all.
I'm gonna need some volunteers
for my first effect.
I-I don't call them tricks
because I think tricks are mean
and what we're here to do
is to have some fun.
What about you two lovebirds
over there?
- You here on your honeymoon?
- Uh, no.
We're just... just passing through.
We got an R.V.
Oh, great.
Don't tell me where you're from.
But here, we're gonna start real simple.
I'm gonna tell you the town
that you folks left from
and the town that you folks
are headed to.
Just write it down there
on that there piece of paper.
And as you do it, imagine them.
Imagine yourself pulling out
of the driveway.
Lily Soto. You look like you should be
up here being my assistant.
Ladies and gentlemen
Lily Soto.
Okay, now I said that I would discover
the town that you folks are from
and the town that you folks
are headed to.
I believe you started out
in Albuquerque
and you are headed to...
to Seattle, Washington.
How'd I do, Lily?
"Albuquerque and Seattle."
Thank you very much for your help.
You can take a seat. Lily...
I'm not done with you yet.
You have to stay up here and help me.
I wrote down a prediction yesterday
and I gave it to you, yes?
- You did.
- Yes.
- Did you peek at it? Are you sure?
- No, I didn't peek at it.
- I am positive.
- No little peeky-peeks?
No peeks.
And what did I say I'd predict?
Uh, what I had for breakfast
this morning.
Okay. That is impossible.
Uh, and I have to admit...
I told a little white lie.
That is not what I wrote down.
In fact, what I wrote down...
was the name of Hollis Percy's killer.
That's right. Yes.
I have an envelope, too.
And inside this envelope...
I wrote down the reason
for this brutal murder...
the motive, if you will.
Now, Lily, if you would please
open your envelope
and read out that name.
I... do I have to?
I'm afraid you do.
Ian Percy.
Okay, Mr. Jane, that's quite enough.
All right, this is insane.
Did you put him up to this?
- Why would I do that?
- Why, indeed?
Be-because he wants to get rid of me?
I don't know.
He's trying to frame me.
Well, if he's lying, then... then...
you wouldn't object to Lily
opening this envelope
and reading what's inside.
Francisco, shut this travesty down.
Uh, can't do that.
This is a CBI matter.
- Right, Lisbon?
- Yes. I am afraid so.
Ian, either Lily reads out aloud
the reason you killed your father
for everyone to hear
or you come with us...
right now and confess.
- The choice is yours.
- What's happening?
I don't know. And... and I don't know
what you think happened
but whatever's on that paper
it... it's not true.
I think you do know.
And the clock is ticking.
Are you ready, Lily?
Ian, when Lily reads what's inside
I can't control what happens next.
- Okay, I'll read it myself.
- No. No.
Not... not now. Not... not here.
I'm sorry, folks.
I'll come with you, all right?
Please, look, whatever you want.
Wise choice.
Ian Percy, you're under arrest for murder.
- Ian? Ian!
- It's... it's okay, Mom.
It's gonna be okay.
You were dating Lily, right?
On the downlow?
I thought Dad wouldn't approve.
He thought the Percy name
was something special.
And she wasn't like us.
How'd you know?
That you two are in love?
Oh, that was easy.
Then there were little things...
little things that said
that there was something, uh...
off.
You know, everybody thought
my dad was some good guy.
And that he kept the town going,
you know?
But they didn't know...
how he terrorized us, that...
He wasn't fit...
not to raise a family.
We need to know how it happened.
Start a month ago?
Oh, it started before that.
When I first moved back
from San Francisco
"it was like a few months ago."
"Meeting Lily was..."
"It was like a dream."
And I figured he...
he knew something
when he started drinking again.
He was too ashamed to come
to me, so...
I went to him.
And he was drunk.
I didn't know about his affair.
I mean, how could I have even guessed?
"I'm trying to tell you..."
"Lily is your sister."
"No. No, that is absurd."
- "No. No, she can't... no!"
- "I know my own daughter."
"We didn't think
you were coming back."
- "You abandoned us."
- "Mom knows?"
"No, of course not."
"Lily's mother and me are kind of a..."
"a fling! You know, we were young..."
"30 years ago."
- "How could you do this to me?"
- "Do this to you?"
"You spoiled brat."
"What the hell did I ever do to you?"
"I betrayed your mother not you
and that's my business."
"Lily and you..."
"That's on you.
You should've been able to tell."
"So it's my fault, huh?"
"It's not mine. Either way...
It doesn't matter."
"So, son, you gotta suck it up
and move on!"
"Lily is not for you."
"She's the only girl I've ever loved!"
"I wanna marry her!"
"For the first time in your life, son"
"face the facts that are staring you
in the face"
"and stop whining!"
What do I even say to her?
"Dad had an affair."
Um...
"I'm your brother."
It's not gonna be easy.
But you are gonna have to tell her
the truth at some point.
I finally got through to him, you know?
It felt good... for a second
that the old bastard finally understood.
When he was dying, he...
finally understood
what he'd done to all of us.
- Hey.
You fooled a guy
with a mobile made-up arson lab?
- Neat trick.
- He didn't seem to think so, but thanks.
- So... good week then?
- Yeah. Yeah.
Great, yeah.
Just moving with the wind.
No, I'm sorry. That was a lie.
Uh, today is not a good day.
- We have to talk.
- Okay. About what?
- About you and me.
- Great.
Because there's something I really
have been meaning to tell you, um...
I...
- Excuse me.
- Oh, hi!
- I'm sorry I'm late. Traffic was just...
- It's fine.
Oh, uh, uh, Duncan, this is Wayne.
Wayne, Duncan.
- Wayne Rigsby. It's good to meet you.
- Pleasure.
Wayne and I met in Los Angeles
at the White Hat program.
Actually that's... that's where we met.
- What did I say?
- Y-you said, "Wayne".
Oh, s... I'm sorry.
Weird...
Oh! I just remembered
I left something at my desk.
Duncan, it's great to meet you.